34820783202111251573-28002021Nov24Archives of sexual behaviorArch Sex Behav"White, Tall, Top, Masculine, Muscular": Narratives of Intracommunity Stigma in Young Sexual Minority Men's Experience on Mobile Apps.10.1007/s10508-021-02144-zWhat forms of intracommunity stigma do young sexual minority men narrate as they participate in communities through mobile apps? In a content analysis of 32 interviews with a racially diverse sample of young sexual minority men (ages 19-25; 84.4% non-White) from four regions of the USA, a majority of men (62.5%) spontaneously discussed mobile apps (e.g., Grindr, Scruff) when asked about their experience of community more broadly. Men's narratives revealed engagement with intracommunity stigma related to body size, race/ethnicity, gender expression, and sexual position (e.g., bottom). Stigma related to HIV status, substance use, and social class were not spontaneously narrated in response to questions about men's experience in communities. Expressions of stigma were frequently experienced intersectionally, particularly regarding racialized stereotype expectations (e.g., "Asian men are twinks, effeminate"). We discuss the ways in which sexual minority men reproduce dominant ideologies related to racism, misogyny, and masculine body ideals as they engage with one another on mobile apps. To the extent that many young men rely on mobile apps for community connection, their experiences of community might serve to exacerbate, rather than ameliorate, the deleterious impact of stigma.© 2021. The Author(s).HammackPhillip LPLhttp://orcid.org/0000-0003-2203-858XDepartment of Psychology, University of California, Santa Cruz, 1156 High Street, Santa Cruz, CA, 95054, USA. hammack@ucsc.edu.GreccoBrockBSocial Science Interdepartmental Program, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA.WilsonBianca D MBDMWilliams Institute, UCLA School of Law, Los Angeles, CA, USA.MeyerIlan HIHWilliams Institute, UCLA School of Law, Los Angeles, CA, USA.eng1R01HD078526Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human DevelopmentJournal Article20211124United StatesArch Sex Behav12735160004-0002IMCommunityGay menIntersectionalitySexual orientationSocial mediaStigma2021033020210830202108272021112564720211126602021112660aheadofprint3482078310.1007/s10508-021-02144-z10.1007/s10508-021-02144-zAbelson, M. J. (2019). Men in place: Trans masculinity, race, and sexuality in America. University of Minnesota Press.10.5749/j.ctvc5pc1mAhmed, A. K., Weatherburn, P., Reid, D., Hickson, F., Torres-Rueda, S., Steinberg, P., & Bourne, A. (2016). Social norms related to combining drugs and sex (‘chemsex’) among gay men in South London. International Journal of Drug Policy, 38, 29–35. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugpo.2016.10.00710.1016/j.drugpo.2016.10.00727842251Appleby, G. A. (2001). Ethnographic study of gay and bisexual working-class men in the United States. Journal of Gay & Lesbian Social Services, 12(3–4), 51–62. https://doi.org/10.1300/J041v12n03_0410.1300/J041v12n03_04Atkins, D. (2012). Looking queer: Body image and identity in lesbian, bisexual, gay, and transgender communities. Routledge. https://doi.org/10.4324/978020304747710.4324/9780203047477Baams, L., Jonas, K. J., Utz, S., Bos, H. M. W., & van der Vuurst, L. (2011). Internet use and online social support among same-sex attracted individuals of different ages. Computers in Human Behavior, 27(5), 1820–1827. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2011.04.00210.1016/j.chb.2011.04.002Badgett, M. V. L., Choi, S. K., & Wilson, B. D. M., (2019, October). LGBT poverty in the United States: A study of differences between sexual orientation and gender identity groups. The Williams Institute. Retrieved from https://escholarship.org/uc/item/37b617z8 .Barrett, D. C., & Pollack, L. M. (2005). Whose gay community? Social class, sexual self-expression, and gay community involvement. Sociological Quarterly, 46(3), 437–456. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1533-8525.2005.00021.x10.1111/j.1533-8525.2005.00021.xBlackwell, C., Birnholtz, J., & Abbott, C. (2015). Seeing and being seen: Co-situation and impression formation using Grindr, a location-aware gay dating app. New Media & Society, 17(7), 1117–1136. https://doi.org/10.1177/146144481452159510.1177/1461444814521595Bowleg, L. (2013). “Once you’ve blended the cake, you can’t take the parts back to the main ingredients”: Black gay and bisexual men’s descriptions and experiences of intersectionality. Sex Roles, 68(11), 754–767. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11199-012-0152-410.1007/s11199-012-0152-4Boyle, S. C., LaBrie, J. W., & Omoto, A. M. (2020). Normative substance use antecedents among sexual minorities: A scoping review and synthesis. Psychology of Sexual Orientation and Gender Diversity, 7(2), 117–131. https://doi.org/10.1037/sgd000037310.1037/sgd0000373340798458168923Brennan, D. J., Asakura, K., George, C., Newman, P. A., Giwa, S., Hart, T. A., Souleymanov, R., & Betancourt, G. (2013). “Never reflected anywhere”: Body image among ethnoracialized gay and bisexual men. Body Image, 10(3), 389–398. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bodyim.2013.03.00610.1016/j.bodyim.2013.03.00623648108Breslow, A. S., Sandil, R., Brewster, M. E., Parent, M. C., Chan, A., Yucel, A., Bensmiller, N., & Glaeser, E. (2020). Adonis on the apps: Online objectification, self-esteem, and sexual minority men. Psychology of Men & Masculinities, 21(1), 25–35. https://doi.org/10.1037/men000020210.1037/men0000202Bruner, J. S. (1990). Acts of meaning. Harvard University Press.Byron, P., Albury, K., & Pym, T. (2021). Hooking up with friends: LGBTQ+ young people, dating apps, friendship and safety. Media, Culture & Society, 43(3), 497–514. https://doi.org/10.1177/016344372097231210.1177/0163443720972312Callander, D., Newman, C. E., & Holt, M. (2015). Is sexual racism really racism? Distinguishing attitudes toward sexual racism and generic racism among gay and bisexual men. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 44(7), 1991–2000. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-015-0487-310.1007/s10508-015-0487-326149367Callen, A. (2018). Looking at men: Art, anatomy and the modern male body. Yale University Press.Calzo, J. P., Corliss, H. L., Blood, E. A., Field, A. E., & Austin, S. B. (2013). Development of muscularity and weight concerns in heterosexual and sexual minority males. Health Psychology, 32(1), 42–51. https://doi.org/10.1037/a002896410.1037/a0028964233168523718034Cascalheira, C. J., & Smith, B. A. (2020). Hierarchy of desire: Partner preferences and social identities of men who have sex with men on geosocial networks. Sexuality & Culture, 24, 630–648. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12119-019-09653-z10.1007/s12119-019-09653-zCassidy, E. (2018). Gay men, identity, and social media: A culture of participatory reluctance. Routledge.10.4324/9781315737027Chow, J. (2021). No fats, no fems, no problems? Working out and the gay muscled body. Sexualities. https://doi.org/10.1177/1363460721101833110.1177/13634607211018331Collins, P. H. (1986). Learning from the outsider within: The sociological significance of Black feminist thought. Social Problems, 33(6), S14–S32. https://doi.org/10.2307/80067210.2307/800672Compton, W. M., & Jones, C. M. (2021). Substance use among men who have sex with men. New England Journal of Medicine, 385, 352–356. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra203300710.1056/NEJMra2033007Connell, R. W., Dowsett, G. W., Rodden, P., Davis, M. D., Watson, L., & Baxter, D. (1991). Social class, gay men and AIDS prevention. Australian Journal of Public Health, 15(3), 178–189. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-6405.1991.tb00332.x10.1111/j.1753-6405.1991.tb00332.x1932323Conner, C. T. (2019). The gay gayze: Expressions of inequality on Grindr. Sociological Quarterly, 60(3), 397–419. https://doi.org/10.1080/00380253.2018.153339410.1080/00380253.2018.1533394Coston, B. M., & Kimmel, M. (2012). Seeing privilege where it isn’t: Marginalized masculinities and the intersectionality of privilege. Journal of Social Issues, 68(1), 97–111. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4560.2011.01738.x10.1111/j.1540-4560.2011.01738.xCourtenay-Quirk, C., Wolitski, R. J., Parsons, J. T., & Gómez, C. A. (2006). Is HIV/AIDS stigma dividing the gay community? Perceptions of HIV-positive men who have sex with men. AIDS Education and Prevention, 18(1), 56–67. https://doi.org/10.1521/aeap.2006.18.1.5610.1521/aeap.2006.18.1.5616539576Cyrus, K. (2017). Multiple minorities as multiply marginalized: Applying the minority stress theory to LGBTQ people of color. Journal of Gay & Lesbian Mental Health, 21(3), 194–202. https://doi.org/10.1080/19359705.2017.132073910.1080/19359705.2017.1320739Davis, M., Flowers, P., Lorimer, K., Oakland, J., & Frankis, J. (2016). Location, safety and (non) strangers in gay men’s narratives on “hook-up” apps. Sexualities, 19(7), 836–852. https://doi.org/10.1177/136346071662933410.1177/1363460716629334Dimock, M. (2019). Defining generations: Where Millennials end and Generation Z begins. Pew Research Center. Retrieved from https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2019/01/17/where-millennials-end-and-generation-z-begins/ .Dubov, A., Galbo, P., Altice, F. L., & Fraenkel, L. (2018). Stigma and shame experiences by MSM who take PrEP for HIV prevention: A qualitative study. American Journal of Men’s Health, 12(6), 1832–1843. https://doi.org/10.1177/155798831879743710.1177/1557988318797437Filice, E., Raffoul, A., Meyer, S. B., & Neiterman, E. (2019). The influence of Grindr, a geosocial networking application, on body image in gay, bisexual and other men who have sex with men: An exploratory study. Body Image, 31, 59–70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bodyim.2019.08.00710.1016/j.bodyim.2019.08.00731446375Filice, E., Raffoul, A., Meyer, S. B., & Neiterman, E. (2020). The impact of social media on body image perceptions and bodily practices among gay, bisexual, and other men who have sex with men: A critical review of the literature and extension of theory. Sex Roles, 82, 387–410. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11199-019-01063-710.1007/s11199-019-01063-7Frederick, B. J., & Perrone, D. (2014). “Party N Play” on the internet: Subcultural formation, Craigslist, and escaping from stigma. Deviant Behavior, 35(11), 859–884. https://doi.org/10.1080/01639625.2014.89711610.1080/01639625.2014.897116Frost, D. M., Hammack, P. L., Wilson, B. D. M., Krueger, E. A., Kittle, K. R., & Meyer, I. H. (2018). Methodology and technical notes: Generations qualitative interviews recruitment and enrollment. Retrieved from http://www.generations-study.com/methods .Frost, D. M., Hammack, P. L., Wilson, B. D. M., Russell, S. T., Lightfoot, M., & Meyer, I. H. (2020). The qualitative interview in psychology and the study of social change: Sexual identity development, minority stress, and health in the Generations Study. Qualitative Psychology, 7(3), 245–266. https://doi.org/10.1037/qup000014810.1037/qup000014834095332Frost, D. M., Meyer, I. H., & Schwartz, S. (2016). Social support networks among diverse sexual minority populations. American Journal of Orthopsychiatry, 86(1), 91–102. https://doi.org/10.1037/ort000011710.1037/ort0000117Gamarel, K. E., Reisner, S. L., Parsons, J. T., & Golub, S. (2012). Association between socioeconomic position discrimination and psychological distress: Findings from a community-based sample of gay and bisexual men in New York City. American Journal of Public Health, 102(11), 2094–2101. https://doi.org/10.2105/AJPH.2012.30066810.2105/AJPH.2012.300668229941883477964Gaspar, M., Marshall, Z., Adam, B. D., Brennan, D. J., Cox, J., Lachowsky, N., Lambert, G., Moore, D., Hart, T. A., & Grace, D. (2021). “I was just doing what a normal gay man would do, right?”: The biopolitics of substance use and the mental health of sexual minority men. Health. https://doi.org/10.1177/136345932199675310.1177/136345932199675333631980Gluckman, A., & Reed, B. (2012). Homo economics: Capitalism, community, and lesbian and gay life. Routledge.10.4324/9780203610596Grindr. (2018). Kindr Grindr. Retrieved from https://www.kindr.grindr.com .Grosskopf, N. A., LeVasseur, M. T., & Glaser, D. B. (2014). Use of the internet and mobile-based “apps” for sex-seeking among men who have sex with men in New York City. American Journal of Men’s Health, 8(6), 510–520. https://doi.org/10.1177/155798831452731110.1177/155798831452731124658284Gudelunas, D. (2012). There’s an app for that: The uses and gratifications of online social networks for gay men. Sexuality & Culture, 16(4), 347–365. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12119-012-9127-410.1007/s12119-012-9127-4Hale, S. E., & Ojeda, T. (2018). Acceptable femininity? Gay male misogyny and the policing of queer femininities. European Journal of Women’s Studies, 25(3), 310–324. https://doi.org/10.1177/135050681876476210.1177/1350506818764762Hammack, P. L. (2018). Gay men’s identity development in the twenty-first century: Continuity and change, normalization and resistance. Human Development, 61(2), 101–125. https://doi.org/10.1159/00048646910.1159/000486469Hammack, P. L., Frost, D. M., Meyer, I. H., & Pletta, D. R. (2018a). Gay men’s health and identity: Social change and the life course. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 47, 59–74. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-017-0990-910.1007/s10508-017-0990-928585157Hammack, P. L., Meyer, I. H., Krueger, E. A., Lightfoot, M., & Frost, D. M. (2018b). HIV testing and pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) use, familiarity, and attitudes among gay and bisexual men in the United States: A national probability sample of three birth cohorts. PLoS ONE, 13(9), e0202806. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.020280610.1371/journal.pone.0202806301927916128476Hammack, P. L., Toolis, E. E., Wilson, B. D. M., Clark, R. C., & Frost, D. M. (2019). Making meaning of the impact of pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) on public health and sexual culture: Narratives of three generations of gay and bisexual men. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 48(4), 1041–1058. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-019-1417-610.1007/s10508-019-1417-6308749787175836Han, C. (2008). A qualitative exploration of the relationship between racism and unsafe sex among Asian Pacific Islander gay men. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 37(5), 827–837. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-007-9308-710.1007/s10508-007-9308-718286364Han, C. S. (2006). Geisha of a different kind: Gay Asian men and the gendering of sexual identity. Sexuality & Culture, 10(3), 3–28. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12119-006-1018-010.1007/s12119-006-1018-0Han, C. S., & Choi, K. H. (2018). Very few people say “no Whites”: Gay men of color and the racial politics of desire. Sociological Spectrum, 38(3), 145–161. https://doi.org/10.1080/02732173.2018.146944410.1080/02732173.2018.1469444309061026426121Hawkins, B. W., Armstrong, H. L., Kesselring, S., Rich, A. J., Cui, Z., Sereda, P., Howard, T., Forrest, J. I., Moore, D. M., Lachowsky, N. J., Hogg, R. S., & Roth, E. A. (2019). Substance use as a mechanism for social inclusion among gay, bisexual, and other men who have sex with men in Vancouver, Canada. Substance Use & Misuse, 54(12), 1945–1955. https://doi.org/10.1080/10826084.2019.162190110.1080/10826084.2019.1621901Heaphy, B. (2011). Gay identities and the culture of class. Sexualities, 14(1), 42–62. https://doi.org/10.1177/136346071039056310.1177/1363460710390563Hennen, P. (2005). Bear bodies, bear masculinity: Recuperation, resistance, or retreat? Gender & Society, 19, 25–43. https://doi.org/10.1177/089124320426940810.1177/0891243204269408Heritage, F., & Baker, P. (2021). Crime or culture? Representations of chemsex in the British press and magazines aimed at GBTQ+ men. Critical Discourse Studies. https://doi.org/10.1080/17405904.2021.191005210.1080/17405904.2021.1910052Holt, M. (2011). Gay men and ambivalence about “gay community”: From gay community attachment to personal communities. Culture, Health & Sexuality, 13(8), 857–871. https://doi.org/10.1080/13691058.2011.58139010.1080/13691058.2011.581390Hsieh, H.-F., & Shannon, S. E. (2005). Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qualitative Health Research, 15(9), 1277–1288. https://doi.org/10.1177/104973230527668710.1177/104973230527668716204405Hughto, J. M. W., Pachankis, J. E., Eldahan, A. I., & Keene, D. E. (2017). “You can’t just walk down the street and meet someone”: The intersection of social–sexual networking technology, stigma, and health among gay and bisexual men in the small city. American Journal of Men’s Health, 11(3), 726–736. https://doi.org/10.1177/155798831667956310.1177/1557988316679563Hunt, C. J., Fasoli, F., Carnaghi, A., & Cadinu, M. (2016). Masculine self-presentation and distancing from femininity in gay men: An experimental examination of the role of masculinity threat. Psychology of Men & Masculinity, 17(1), 108–112. https://doi.org/10.1037/a003954510.1037/a0039545Hutchinson, D. L. (1999). Ignoring the sexualization of race: Heteronormativity, critical race theory and anti-racist politics. Buffalo Law Review, 47(1), 1–116.Jaspal, R. (2017). Gay men’s construction and management of identity on Grindr. Sexuality & Culture, 21(1), 187–204. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12119-016-9389-310.1007/s12119-016-9389-3Josselson, R., & Hammack, P. L. (2021). Essentials of narrative analysis. American Psychological Association Press.10.1037/0000246-000Levitt, H. M., Bamberg, M., Creswell, J. W., Frost, D. M., Josselson, R., & Suarez-Orozco, C. (2018). Journal article reporting standards for qualitative primary, qualitative meta-analytic, and mixed methods research in psychology: The APA Publications and Communications Board Task Force Report. American Psychologist, 73(1), 26–46. https://doi.org/10.1037/amp000015110.1037/amp0000151Levitt, H. M., Motulsky, S. L., Wertz, F. J., Morrow, S. L., & Ponterotto, J. G. (2017). Recommendations for designing and reviewing qualitative research in psychology: Promoting methodological integrity. Qualitative Psychology, 4(1), 2–22. https://doi.org/10.1037/qup000008210.1037/qup0000082Loiacano, D. K. (1989). Gay identity issues among Black Americans: Racism, homophobia, and the need for validation. Journal of Counseling & Development, 68(1), 21–25. https://doi.org/10.1002/j.1556-6676.1989.tb02486.x10.1002/j.1556-6676.1989.tb02486.xLu, A., LeBlanc, A. J., & Frost, D. M. (2019). Masculinity and minority stress among men in same-sex relationships. Society and Mental Health, 9(2), 259–275. https://doi.org/10.1177/215686931877342510.1177/215686931877342532864183Macapagal, K., Kraus, A., Moskowitz, D. A., & Birnholtz, J. (2020). Geosocial networking application use, characteristics of app-met sexual partners, and sexual behavior among sexual and gender minority adolescents assigned male at birth. Journal of Sex Research, 57(8), 1078–1087. https://doi.org/10.1080/00224499.2019.169800410.1080/00224499.2019.169800431846592Madill, A., Jordan, A., & Shirley, C. (2000). Objectivity and reliability in qualitative analysis: Realist, contextualist and radical constructionist epistemologies. British Journal of Psychology, 91(1), 1–20. https://doi.org/10.1348/00071260016164610.1348/00071260016164610717768Manago, A. M. (2015). Identity development in the digital age: The case of social networking sites. In K. C. McLean & M. Syed (Eds.), The Oxford handbook of identity development (pp. 508–524). Oxford University Press.Manley, E., Levitt, H. M., & Mosher, C. M. (2007). Understanding the bear movement in gay male culture. Journal of Homosexuality, 53(4), 89–112. https://doi.org/10.1080/0091836080210336510.1080/0091836080210336518689193McConnell, E. A., Janulis, P., Phillips, G., Truong, R., & Birkett, M. (2018). Multiple minority stress and LGBT community resilience among sexual minority men. Psychology of Sexual Orientation and Gender Diversity, 5(1), 1–12. https://doi.org/10.1037/sgd000026510.1037/sgd0000265295462285846479McCutcheon, J. M., & Morrison, M. A. (2021). Beyond the superordinate categories of “gay men” and “lesbian women”: Identification of gay and lesbian subgroups. Journal of Homosexuality, 68(1), 112–137. https://doi.org/10.1080/00918369.2019.162712910.1080/00918369.2019.162712931237490Meyer, I. H. (2003). Prejudice, social stress, and mental health in lesbian, gay, and bisexual populations: Conceptual issues and research evidence. Psychological Bulletin, 129(5), 674–697. https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.129.5.67410.1037/0033-2909.129.5.674129565392072932Meyer, I. H., Schwartz, S., & Frost, D. M. (2008). Social patterning of stress and coping: Does disadvantaged social status confer more stress and fewer coping resources? Social Science & Medicine, 67(3), 368–379. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2008.03.01210.1016/j.socscimed.2008.03.012Miller, B. (2015). “They’re the modern-day gay bar”: Exploring the uses and gratifications of social networks for men who have sex with men. Computers in Human Behavior, 51, 476–482. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2015.05.02310.1016/j.chb.2015.05.023Miller, B. (2018). Textually presenting masculinity and the body on mobile dating apps for men who have sex with men. Journal of Men’s Studies, 26(3), 305–326. https://doi.org/10.1177/106082651877341710.1177/1060826518773417Miller, B., & Behm-Morawitz, E. (2020). Investigating the cultivation of masculinity and body self-attitudes for users of mobile dating apps for men who have sex with men. Psychology of Men & Masculinities, 21(2), 266–277. https://doi.org/10.1037/men000022110.1037/men0000221Moskowitz, D. A., & Roloff, M. E. (2017). Recognition and construction of top, bottom, and versatile orientations in gay/bisexual men. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 46, 273–285. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-016-0810-710.1007/s10508-016-0810-727734170Mowlabocus, S. (2021). A Kindr Grindr: Moderating race (ism) in techno-spaces of desire. In R. Ramos & S. Mowlabocus (Eds.), Queer sites in global contexts: Technologies, spaces, and otherness (pp. 33–47). Routledge.Murnen, S. K., & Karazsia, B. T. (2017). A review of research on men’s body image and drive for muscularity. In R. F. Levant & Y. J. Wong (Eds.), The psychology of men and masculinities (pp. 229–257). American Psychological Association Press.10.1037/0000023-009Pachankis, J. E., Clark, K. A., Burton, C. L., Hughto, J. M. W., Bränström, R., & Keene, D. E. (2020). Sex, status, competition, and exclusion: Intraminority stress from within the gay community and gay and bisexual men’s mental health. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 119(3), 713–740. https://doi.org/10.1037/pspp000028210.1037/pspp0000282319280267354883Parsons, J. T., Schrimshaw, E. W., Wolitski, R. J., Halkitis, P. N., Purcell, D. W., Hoff, C. C., & Gomez, C. A. (2005). Sexual harm reduction practices of HIV-seropositive gay and bisexual men: Serosorting, strategic positioning, and withdrawal before ejaculation. AIDS, 19(Supplement 1), S13–S25. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.aids.0000167348.15750.9a10.1097/01.aids.0000167348.15750.9a15838191Peacock, B., Eyre, S. L., Quinn, S. C., & Kegeles, S. (2001). Delineating differences: Sub-communities in the San Francisco gay community. Culture, Health & Sexuality, 3(2), 183–201. https://doi.org/10.1080/13691050175015300310.1080/136910501750153003Poon, M.K.-L., & Ho, P.T.-T. (2008). Negotiating social stigma among gay Asian men. Sexualities, 11(1–2), 245–268. https://doi.org/10.1177/136346070708547210.1177/1363460707085472Pym, T., Byron, P., & Albury, K. (2021). “I still want to know they’re not terrible people”: Negotiating “queer community” on dating apps. International Journal of Cultural Studies, 24(3), 398–413. https://doi.org/10.1177/136787792095933210.1177/1367877920959332Ramirez, J. L., & Galupo, M. P. (2019). Multiple minority stress: The role of proximal and distal stress on mental health outcomes among lesbian, gay, and bisexual people of color. Journal of Gay & Lesbian Mental Health, 23(2), 145–167. https://doi.org/10.1080/19359705.2019.156894610.1080/19359705.2019.1568946Ravenhill, J. P., & de Visser, R. O. (2017). Perceptions of gay men’s masculinity are associated with their sexual self-label, voice quality and physique. Psychology & Sexuality, 8(3), 208–222. https://doi.org/10.1080/19419899.2017.134374610.1080/19419899.2017.1343746Ravenhill, J. P., & de Visser, R. O. (2018). “It takes a man to put me on the bottom”: Gay men’s experiences of masculinity and anal intercourse. Journal of Sex Research, 55(8), 1033–1047. https://doi.org/10.1080/00224499.2017.140354710.1080/00224499.2017.140354729220585Renninger, B. J. (2019). Grindr killed the gay bar, and other attempts to blame social technologies for urban development: A democratic approach to popular technologies and queer sociality. Journal of Homosexuality, 66(12), 1736–1755. https://doi.org/10.1080/00918369.2018.151420510.1080/00918369.2018.151420530222066Riggs, D. W. (2013). Anti-Asian sentiment amongst a sample of White Australian men on Gaydar. Sex Roles, 68(11–12), 768–778. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11199-012-0119-510.1007/s11199-012-0119-5Roberts, S. O., & Rizzo, M. T. (2021). The psychology of American racism. American Psychologist, 76(3), 475–487. https://doi.org/10.1037/amp000064210.1037/amp0000642Rosengren, A. L., Menza, T. W., LeGrand, S., Muessig, K. E., Bauermeister, J. A., & Hightow-Weidman, L. B. (2019). Stigma and mobile app use among young Black men who have sex with men. AIDS Education and Prevention, 31(6), 523–537.10.1521/aeap.2019.31.6.523Ruez, D. (2017). “I never felt targeted as an Asian…until I went to a gay pub”: Sexual racism and the aesthetic geographies of the bad encounter. Environment and Planning A, 49(4), 893–210. https://doi.org/10.1177/0308518X1668081710.1177/0308518X16680817Sánchez, F. J., & Vilain, E. (2012). “Straight-acting gays”: The relationship between masculine consciousness, anti-effeminacy, and negative gay identity. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 41(1), 111–119. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-012-9912-z10.1007/s10508-012-9912-z22323055Sarson, C. (2020). “Hey man, how’s u?”: Masculine speech and straight-acting gay men online. Journal of Gender Studies, 29(8), 897–910. https://doi.org/10.1080/09589236.2020.179480210.1080/09589236.2020.1794802Skidmore, W. C., Linsenmeier, J. A. W., & Bailey, J. M. (2006). Gender nonconformity and psychological distress in lesbians and gay men. Archives of Sexual Behavior, 35(6), 685–697. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-006-9108-510.1007/s10508-006-9108-517109224Smit, P. J., Brady, M., Carter, M., Fernandes, R., Lamore, L., Meulbroek, M., Ohayon, M., Platteau, T., Rehberg, P., Rockstroh, J. K., & Thompson, M. (2012). HIV-related stigma within communities of gay men: A literature review. AIDS Care, 24(3–4), 405–412. https://doi.org/10.1080/09540121.2011.61391010.1080/09540121.2011.61391022117138Spence, D. P. (1984). Narrative truth and historical truth: Meaning and interpretation in psychoanalysis. Norton.Tan, R. K. J., Wong, C. M., Chen, M. I., Chan, Y. Y., Bin Ibrahim, M. A., Lim, O. Z., Chio, M. T., Wong, C. S., Chan, R. K., Chua, L. J., & Choong, B. C. H. (2018). Chemsex among gay, bisexual, and other men who have sex with men in Singapore and the challenges ahead: A qualitative study. International Journal of Drug Policy, 61, 31–37. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugpo.2018.10.00210.1016/j.drugpo.2018.10.00230388567Taylor, S. H., Hutson, J. A., & Alicea, T. R. (2017). Social consequences of Grindr use: Extending the internet-enhanced self-disclosure hypothesis. In Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems—CHI ’17 (pp. 6645–6657). https://doi.org/10.1145/3025453.3025775 .Taywaditep, K. J. (2002). Marginalization among the marginalized. Journal of Homosexuality, 42(1), 1–28. https://doi.org/10.1300/J082v42n01_0110.1300/J082v42n01_01Thoma, B. C., Eckstrand, K. L., Montano, G. T., Rezeppa, T. L., & Marshal, M. P. (2021). Gender nonconformity and minority stress among lesbian, gay, and bisexual individuals: A meta-analytic review. Perspectives on Psychological Science, 16, 1165–1183. https://doi.org/10.1177/174569162096876610.1177/174569162096876633645322Tran, A., Kaplan, J. A., Austin, B., Davison, K., Lopez, G., & Agénor, M. (2020). “It’s all outward appearance-based attractions”: A qualitative study of body image among a sample of young gay and bisexual men. Journal of Gay & Lesbian Mental Health, 24(3), 281–307. https://doi.org/10.1080/19359705.2019.170668310.1080/19359705.2019.1706683Treloar, C., Hopwood, M., Drysdale, K., Lea, T., Holt, M., Dowsett, G. W., Aggleton, P., & Bryant, J. (2021). Stigma as understood by key informants: A social ecological approach to gay and bisexual men’s use of crystal methamphetamine for sex. International Journal of Drug Policy. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugpo.2021.10322910.1016/j.drugpo.2021.10322934610884Underwood, S. G. (2012). Gay men and anal eroticism: Tops, bottoms, and versatiles. Routledge. https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203057216Valocchi, S. (1999). The class-inflected nature of gay identity. Social Problems, 46(2), 207–224. https://doi.org/10.2307/309725310.2307/3097253Van De Wiele, C., & Tong, S. T. (2014). Breaking boundaries: The uses and gratifications of Grindr. In UbiComp ’14: Proceedings of the 2014 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing (pp. 619–630). https://doi.org/10.1145/2632048.2636070 .Vogel, E., Rose, J., Roberts, L., & Eckles, K. (2014). Social comparison, social media, and self-esteem. Psychology of Popular Media Culture, 3, 206–222. https://doi.org/10.1037/ppm000004710.1037/ppm0000047Wilson, B. D. M., Harper, G. W., Hidalgo, M. A., Jamil, O. B., Torres, R. S., Fernandez, M. I., & Adolescent Medicine Trials Network for HIV/AIDS Interventions. (2010). Negotiating dominant masculinity ideology: Strategies used by gay, bisexual and questioning male adolescents. American Journal of Community Psychology, 45(1–2), 169–185. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10464-009-9291-310.1007/s10464-009-9291-3200822382906685Wu, S., & Ward, J. (2018). The mediation of gay men’s lives: A review on gay dating app studies. Sociology Compass, 12, e12560. https://doi.org/10.1111/soc4.1256010.1111/soc4.12560Zervoulis, K., Smith, D. S., Reed, R., & Dinos, S. (2020). Use of “gay dating apps” and its relationship with individual well-being and sense of community in men who have sex with men. Psychology & Sexuality, 11(1–2), 88–102. https://doi.org/10.1080/19419899.2019.168435410.1080/19419899.2019.1684354