34687240202110291464-54912021Oct23Diabetic medicine : a journal of the British Diabetic AssociationDiabet MedParental experiences of short term supported use of a do-it-yourself continuous glucose monitor (DIYrtCGM): A qualitative study.e1473110.1111/dme.14731To investigate the experiences of parents caring for young children with type 1 diabetes type 1 diabetes using a do-it-yourself continuous glucose monitor (DIYrtCGM) in a supported setting.Exit interviews were conducted with parents from 11 families at the end of the MiaoMiao study: a randomised cross-over trial focusing on parental fear of hypoglycaemia. Technical support was provided to participants while using DIYrtCGM during the trial. A convenience sampling approach was used to recruit parents. An in-depth, semi-structured interview approach was used. Thematic analysis was used to identify key themes and subthemes.Parents identified that remote monitoring enabled proactive management and that overall alarms/glucose alerts were useful. Some parents reported reductions in anxiety, increased independence for their child, and improvements in the child-parent relationship. However, parents also reported regular signal loss with DIYrtCGM, along with complicated apps and challenges troubleshooting technical problems. Despite this, nine of the 11 families continued to use the system after the end of the trial.Do-it-yourself continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) was on balance beneficial for the parents interviewed. However, while access to CGM shifted the burden of care experienced by parents, burden did not significantly reduce for all parents, as the improved glycaemic control that they achieved was accompanied with the responsibility for continually monitoring their child's data. Supported use of do-it-yourself CGM may be an achievable, cost-effective option for parents caring for children with type 1 diabetes in countries without funded access to CGM.© 2021 Diabetes UK.CrocketHamishHTe Huataki Waiora School of Health, University of Waikato, Hamilton, New Zealand.ElbashyMona MMMDepartment of Women's and Children's Health, Dunedin School of Medicine, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.KavanaghTomTTe Huataki Waiora School of Health, University of Waikato, Hamilton, New Zealand.StylesSaraSDepartment of Human Nutrition, Division of Sciences, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.GallandBarbaraBDepartment of Women's and Children's Health, Dunedin School of Medicine, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.HaszardJillian JJJDepartment of Human Nutrition, Division of Sciences, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.WiltshireEskoEDepartment of Paediatrics and Child Health, University of Otago Wellington, Wellington, New Zealand.Paediatrics and Child Health, Capital and Coast District Health Board, Wellington, New Zealand.JefferiesCraigChttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-0541-6094Paediatric Endocrinology, Starship Children's Health, Auckland, New Zealand.Liggins Institute, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.de BockMartin IMIDepartment of Paediatrics, University of Otago Christchurch, Christchurch, New Zealand.Department of Paediatrics, Canterbury District Health Board, Christchurch, New Zealand.TomlinsonPaulPDepartment of Women's and Children's Health, Dunedin School of Medicine, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.Paediatric Endocrinology, Southern District Health Board, Dunedin, New Zealand.JonesShirleySDepartment of Women's and Children's Health, Dunedin School of Medicine, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.WheelerBenjamin JBJDepartment of Women's and Children's Health, Dunedin School of Medicine, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.Paediatric Endocrinology, Southern District Health Board, Dunedin, New Zealand.engLottery Health Research GrantDepartment of Women's and Children's Health, Dunedin School of Medicine, University of OtagoJournal Article20211023EnglandDiabet Med85008580742-3071IMcontinuous glucose monitordo-it-yourselfqualitativetype 1 diabetes2021101720210617202110212021102460202110246020211023836aheadofprint3468724010.1111/dme.14731REFERENCESThe Diabetes Control and Complications Trial Research Group. The effect of intensive treatment of diabetes on the development and progression of long-term complications in insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. N Engl J Med. 1993;329(14):977-986. doi:10.1056/NEJM199309303291401Soltész G. Diabetes in the young: a paediatric and epidemiological perspective. Diabetologia. 2003;46(4):447-454. doi:10.1007/s00125-003-1101-0Sullivan-Bolyai S, Deatrick J, Gruppuso P, Tamborlane W, Grey M. Constant vigilance: mothers’ work parenting young children with type 1 diabetes. J Pediatr Nurs. 2003;18(1):21-29. doi:10.1053/jpdn.2003.4Macaulay GC, Boucher SE, Yogarajah A, Galland BC, Wheeler BJ. Sleep and night-time caregiving in parents of children and adolescents with type 1 diabetes mellitus - a qualitative study. Behav Sleep Med. 2020;18(5):622-636. doi:10.1080/15402002.2019.1647207Monaghan MC, Hilliard ME, Cogen FR, Streisand R. Nighttime caregiving behaviors among parents of young children with type 1 diabetes: associations with illness characteristics and parent functioning. Fam Syst Health. 2009;27(1):28-38. doi:10.1037/a0014770Van Name MA, Hilliard ME, Boyle CT, et al. Nighttime is the worst time: parental fear of hypoglycemia in young children with type 1 diabetes. Pediatr Diabetes. 2018;19(1):114-120.Lawton J, Waugh N, Barnard KD, et al. Challenges of optimizing glycaemic control in children with type 1 diabetes: a qualitative study of parents’ experiences and views. Diabet Med. 2015;32(8):1063-1070. doi:10.1111/dme.12660Freeborn D, Dyches T, Roper SO, Mandleco B. Identifying challenges of living with type 1 diabetes: child and youth perspectives. J Clin Nurs. 2013;22(13-14):1890-1898. doi:10.1111/jocn.12046Castle C, Alsweiler A, Crawford W, et al. Glycaemic control in Otago children with type 1 diabetes. NZ Med Stud J. 2017;25:29-32.McKnight JA, Wild SH, Lamb MJE, et al. Glycaemic control of type 1 diabetes in clinical practice early in the 21st century: an international comparison. Diabet Med. 2015;32(8):1036-1050. doi:10.1111/dme.12676Foster NC, Beck RW, Miller KM, et al. State of type 1 diabetes management and outcomes from the T1D exchange in 2016-2018. Diabetes Technol Ther. 2019;21(2):1-7.Beck RW, Riddlesworth T, Ruedy K, et al. Effect of continuous glucose monitoring on glycemic control in adults with type 1 diabetes using insulin injections: the DIAMOND randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2017;317(4):700-708. doi:10.1001/jama.2016.19975Lind M, Polonsky W, Hirsch IB, et al. Continuous glucose monitoring vs conventional therapy for glycemic control in adults with type 1 diabetes treated with multiple daily insulin injections: the GOLD randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2017;317(4):379-387. doi:10.1001/jama.2016.19976Burckhardt M-A, Roberts A, Smith GJ, Abraham MB, Davis EA, Jones TW. The use of continuous glucose monitoring with remote monitoring improves psychosocial measures in parents of children with type 1 diabetes: a randomized crossover trial. Diabetes Care. 2018;41(12):2641-2643. doi:10.2337/dc18-0938Burckhardt M-A, Fried L, Bebbington K, et al. Use of remote monitoring with continuous glucose monitoring in young children with type 1 diabetes: the parents’ perspective. Diabet Med. 2019;36(11):1453-1459.Lawton J, Blackburn M, Allen J, et al. Patients’ and caregivers’ experiences of using continuous glucose monitoring to support diabetes self-management: qualitative study. BMC Endocr Disord. 2018;18(1):12. doi:10.1186/s12902-018-0239-1Haslund-Thomsen H, Hasselbalch LA, Laugesen B. Parental experiences of continuous glucose monitoring in Danish children with type 1 diabetes mellitus. J Pediatr Nurs. 2020;53:e149-e155.Tanenbaum ML, Zaharieva DP, Addala A, et al. “I Was Ready for it at the Beginning”: parent experiences with early introduction of continuous glucose monitoring following their child’s type 1 diabetes diagnosis. Diabet Med. 2021;38(8):1-9. Available Online Ahead of Print:1-9. doi:https://doi.org/10.1111/dme.14567Elbalshy M, Boucher S, Crocket H, et al. Exploring parental experiences of using a do-it-yourself solution for continuous glucose monitoring among children and adolescents with type 1 diabetes: a qualitative study. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2020;14(5):844-853. Available Online Ahead of Print:1-10. doi:10.1177/1932296819895290Barnard KD, Breton MD. Diabetes technological revolution: winners and losers? J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2018;12(6):1227-1230. doi:10.1177/1932296818788872Heinemann L, Freckmann G. CGM versus FGM; or, continuous glucose monitoring is not flash glucose monitoring. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2015;9(5):947-950. doi:10.1177/1932296815603528Deshmukh H, Wilmot EG, Gregory R, et al. The effect of flash glucose monitoring on glycemic control, diabetes-related distress, and resource utilization in the Association of British Clinical Diabetologists (ABCD) nationwide audit. Diabetes Care. 2020;43(8):1-8. doi:10.2337/dc20-0738Roussel R, Riveline J-P, Vicaut E, et al. Important drop rate of acute diabetes complications in people with type 1 or type 2 diabetes after initiation of flash glucose monitoring in France: the RELIEF study. Diabetes Care. 2021;44:1-10.Barnard KD, Ziegler R, Klonoff DC, et al. Open source closed-loop insulin delivery systems: a clash of cultures or merging of diverse approaches? J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2018;12(6):1223-1226. Available Online Ahead of Print:1-4. doi:10.1177/1932296818792577Elbalshy M, Boucher S, Galland B, et al. The MiaoMiao study: can do-it-yourself continuous glucose monitoring technology improve fear of hypoglycaemia in parents of children affected by type 1 diabetes? J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2020;19:1647-1658. doi:10.1007/s40200-020-00671-5Elbalshy M, Wheeler BJ, Styles S, Haszard JJ, Galland B, Crocket H, Jefferies CA, Wiltshire E, Tomlinson P, de Bock M. The effect of do-it-yourself real-time continuous glucose monitoring on psychological and glycaemic variables in children with type 1 diabetes: a randomised crossover trial. E-poster presented at American Diabetes Association 81st Scientific Sessions, 25-29 June 2021.Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77-101. doi:10.1191/1478088706qp063oaAtkinson J, Salmond C, Crampton P NZDep2013 index of deprivation. University of Otago; 2014:64. Accessed October 8, 2021. https://www.health.govt.nz/publication/nzdep2013-index-deprivationWong JC, Foster NC, Maahs DM, et al. Real-time continuous glucose monitoring among participants in the T1D exchange clinic registry. Dia Care. 2014;37(10):2702-2709. doi:10.2337/dc14-0303Bubblan. Bubblan Home Page. https//:bubblan.org. Accessed 1 September, 2021.Visser MM, Charleer S, Fieuws S, et al. Comparing real-time and intermittently scanned continuous glucose monitoring in adults with type 1 diabetes (ALERTT1): a 6-month, prospective, multicentre, randomised controlled trial. The Lancet. 2021. Available Online Ahead of Print: 1-9. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00789-3