34713173202110302673-253X32021Frontiers in digital healthFront Digit HealthDigital Mental Health for Young People: A Scoping Review of Ethical Promises and Challenges.69707210.3389/fdgth.2021.697072Mental health disorders are complex disorders of the nervous system characterized by a behavioral or mental pattern that causes significant distress or impairment of personal functioning. Mental illness is of particular concern for younger people. The WHO estimates that around 20% of the world's children and adolescents have a mental health condition, a rate that is almost double compared to the general population. One approach toward mitigating the medical and socio-economic effects of mental health disorders is leveraging the power of digital health technology to deploy assistive, preventative, and therapeutic solutions for people in need. We define "digital mental health" as any application of digital health technology for mental health assessment, support, prevention, and treatment. However, there is only limited evidence that digital mental health tools can be successfully implemented in clinical settings. Authors have pointed to a lack of technical and medical standards for digital mental health apps, personalized neurotechnology, and assistive cognitive technology as a possible cause of suboptimal adoption and implementation in the clinical setting. Further, ethical concerns have been raised related to insufficient effectiveness, lack of adequate clinical validation, and user-centered design as well as data privacy vulnerabilities of current digital mental health products. The aim of this paper is to report on a scoping review we conducted to capture and synthesize the growing literature on the promises and ethical challenges of digital mental health for young people aged 0-25. This review seeks to survey the scope and focus of the relevant literature, identify major benefits and opportunities of ethical significance (e.g., reducing suffering and improving well-being), and provide a comprehensive mapping of the emerging ethical challenges. Our findings provide a comprehensive synthesis of the current literature and offer a detailed informative basis for any stakeholder involved in the development, deployment, and management of ethically-aligned digital mental health solutions for young people.Copyright © 2021 Wies, Landers and Ienca.WiesBlancheBDepartment of Health Sciences and Technology, ETH Zurich (Swiss Federal Institut of Technology), Zurich, Switzerland.LandersConstantinCDepartment of Health Sciences and Technology, ETH Zurich (Swiss Federal Institut of Technology), Zurich, Switzerland.IencaMarcelloMDepartment of Health Sciences and Technology, ETH Zurich (Swiss Federal Institut of Technology), Zurich, Switzerland.engJournal ArticleReview20210906SwitzerlandFront Digit Health1017718892673-253Xadolescent and youthdigital healthdigital health (eHealth)ethicsmental healthThe authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.20210418202107062021102963520211030602021103061epublish3471317310.3389/fdgth.2021.697072PMC8521997Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2019 Nov 7;21(11):11631701320NAM Perspect. 2019 Oct 28;2019:34532674Int J Bipolar Disord. 2017 Dec;5(1):628155206BMC Med Ethics. 2018 Feb 23;19(1):1129475437JMIR Ment Health. 2018 Apr 23;5(2):e3229685865Nat Biotechnol. 2018 Sep 6;36(9):805-81030188521Biomed Inform Insights. 2019 Mar 05;11:117822261982908330858710J Med Internet Res. 2018 Jul 30;20(7):e1013130061092Cogn Behav Pract. 2015 Aug 1;22(3):281-29026213458Child Adolesc Psychiatr Clin N Am. 2018 Apr;27(2):133-14329502741Front Psychiatry. 2019 May 01;10:28131118908Int J Bipolar Disord. 2017 Dec;5(1):2628480484Int J Soc Robot. 2020 May 23;:1-1732837630Lancet. 2007 Sep 8;370(9590):878-8917804062J Nerv Ment Dis. 2018 Aug;206(8):662-66630020203N Engl J Med. 2020 Aug 6;383(6):510-51232283003Res Involv Engagem. 2020 Sep 3;6:5132908677Science. 2019 Jan 18;363(6424):234-23530655433JMIR Ment Health. 2019 Dec 4;6(12):e1486631799937Psychiatry Res. 2020 Jun;288:11300332315885Psychol Med. 2019 Jul;49(9):1426-144830744717Front Psychiatry. 2019 May 10;10:34431133906J Med Internet Res. 2010 Jun 18;12(2):e2220562092JAMA Psychiatry. 2020 Sep 1;77(9):891-89232242888Am J Psychiatry. 2014 Jun;171(6):683-9024700332JAMA Psychiatry. 2015 Apr;72(4):334-4125671328Nurs Health Sci. 2013 Sep;15(3):398-40523480423J Med Internet Res. 2019 Jul 22;21(7):e1286931333198JMIR Ment Health. 2020 Mar 26;7(3):e1884832213476J Can Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2016 Spring;25(2):80-627274743Psychiatr Serv. 2017 May 1;68(5):427-42928412890NPJ Digit Med. 2019 Oct 18;2:10431646184Br J Psychiatry. 2016 Oct;209(4):277-28327340111Child Adolesc Psychiatr Clin N Am. 2017 Jan;26(1):117-12427837937Br J Psychiatry. 2016 Oct;209(4):271-27227698212J Med Internet Res. 2019 May 09;21(5):e1321631094356J Affect Disord. 2019 May 1;250:163-16930856493Med Health Care Philos. 2006;9(3):377-8817033883J Alzheimers Dis. 2017;56(4):1301-134028222516J Med Internet Res. 2017 Apr 10;19(4):e10228396301