34726798202111161464-54912021Nov02Diabetic medicine : a journal of the British Diabetic AssociationDiabet MedmHealth apps for gestational diabetes mellitus that provide clinical decision support or artificial intelligence: A scoping review.e1473510.1111/dme.14735Gestational diabetes (GDM) is the most common metabolic disorder of pregnancy, requiring complex management and empowerment of those affected. Mobile health (mHealth) applications (apps) are proposed for streamlining healthcare service delivery, extending care relationships into the community, and empowering those affected by prolonged medical disorders to be equal collaborators in their healthcare. This review investigates mHealth apps intended for use with GDM; specifically those powered by artificial intelligence (AI) or providing decision support.A scoping review using the novel Survey Tool approach for collaborative literature Reviews (STaR) process was performed.From 18 papers, 11 discrete GDM-based mHealth apps were identified, but only 3 were reasonably mature with only one currently in use in a clinical setting. Two-thirds of the apps provided condition-relevant contextual user feedback that could aid in patient self care. However, although each app targeted one or more components of the GDM clinical pathway, no app addressed the entirety from diagnosis to postpartum.There are limited mHealth apps for GDM that incorporate AI or AI-based decision support. Many exist only to record patient information like blood glucose readings or diet, provide generic patient education or advice, or to reduce adverse events by providing medication or appointment alerts. Significant barriers remain that continue to limit the adoption of mHealth apps in clinical care settings. Further research and development are needed to deliver intelligent holistic mHealth apps using AI that can truly reduce healthcare resource use and improve outcomes by enabling patient self care in the community.© 2021 The Authors. Diabetic Medicine published by John Wiley & Sons Ltd on behalf of Diabetes UK.DaleyBridget JBJCentre for Genomics and Child Health, Blizard Institute, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.Ni'ManMichaelMCentre for Genomics and Child Health, Blizard Institute, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.NevesMariana RMRRisk and Information Management, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.Bobby HudaMohammed SMShttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-7303-199XMarshWilliamWRisk and Information Management, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.FentonNorman ENEhttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-2924-0510Risk and Information Management, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.HitmanGraham AGAhttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-6637-9004Centre for Genomics and Child Health, Blizard Institute, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.McLachlanScottShttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-2528-8050Risk and Information Management, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.Edinburgh Law School, University of Edinburgh, Birmingham, UK.engEngineering and Physical Sciences Research CouncilJournal ArticleReview20211102EnglandDiabet Med85008580742-3071IMappsartificial intelligenceclinical decision system supportgestational diabetesmHealthscoping review20211028202107132021103120211136020211136020211121226aheadofprint3472679810.1111/dme.14735REFERENCESMcIntyre HD, Catalano PM, Zhang C, Desoye G, Mathiesen ER, Damm P. Gestational diabetes mellitus. Nat Rev. 2019;5. doi:10.1038/s41572-019-0098-8Greenhalgh T, Clinch M, Afsar N, et al. Socio-cultural influences on the behaviour of South Asian women with diabetes in pregnancy: qualitative study using a multi-level theoretical approach. BMC Med. 2015;13(1):120.WHO. mHealth: New horizons for health through mobile technologies: second global survey on eHealth. Secondary mHealth: New horizons for health through mobile technologies: second global survey on eHealth. 2011.Byambasuren O, Beller E, Glasziou P. Current knowledge and adoption of mobile health apps among Australian general practitioners: survey study. J JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2019;7(6):e13199.Jimenez G, Lum E, Huang Z, Theng YL, Boehm BO, Car J. Reminders for medication adherence in Type 2 diabetes management apps. J Pharm Pract Res. 2020;50(1):78-81.Huang Z, Lum E, Car J. Medication management apps for diabetes: systematic assessment of the transparency and reliability of health information dissemination. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2020;8(2):e15364.Huang Z Smartphone apps for type 2 diabetes self-management and medication adherence: a multi-method study. 2020. https://hdl.handle.net/10356/137883McLachlan S, Paterson H, Dube K, et al. Real-time Online Probabilistic Medical Computation using Bayesian Networks (No. 2744). Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Health Informatics (ICHI 2020); 2020. doi:10.1109/ICHI48887.2020.9374378NICE. Costing statement: Diabetes in pregnancy. Secondary Costing statement: Diabetes in pregnancy. 2015. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng3/resources/costing-statement-pdf-3782989Sutton R, Pincock D, Baumgart D, Sadowski D, Fedorak R, Kroeker K. An overview of clinical decision support systems: benefits, risks, and strategies for success. NPJ Digital Medicine. 2020;3(1):1-10.Immanuel J, Simmonds D. Apps and the woman with gestational diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(2):313-315. doi:10.2337/dci20-0068Garg N, A. SK, Arora S, Kaur K. Application of mobile technology for disease and treatment monitoring of gestational diabetes mellitus among pregnant women: a systematic review. Journal of Diabetes Science and Technology. 2020;1932296820965577.Dube K, McLachlan S, Daley B, Hitman GA, Fento NE, Kyrimi K. Survey Tool approach for collaborative literature Reviews (STaR): Case Studies in Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare. Manuscript under review 2020.Ramesh A, Kambhampati C, Monson JR, Drew P. Artificial intelligence in medicine. Ann R Coll Surg Engl. 2004;86(5):334.Bui X-N, Nguyen H, Le H-A, Bui H-B, Do N-H. Prediction of blast-induced air over-pressure in open-pit mine: assessment of different artificial intelligence techniques. Nat Resour Res. 2020;29(2):571-591.Johnson CM, Johnson TR, Zhang J. A user-centered framework for redesigning health care interfaces. J Biomed Inform. 2005;38(1):75-87.Lauesen S. User interface design: a software engineering perspective. Pearson Education; 2005. https://www.pearson.com.au/products/K-L-Lauesen/User-Interface-Design-A-Software-Engineering-Perspective/9780321181435?R=9780321181435#!Schnall R, Rojas M, Bakken S, et al. A user-centered model for designing consumer mobile health (mHealth) applications (apps). J Biomed Inform. 2016;60:243-251.McCurdie T, Taneva S, Casselman M, et al. mHealth consumer apps: the case for user-centered design. Biomed Instrum Technol. 2012;46(s2):49-56.Farao J, Malila B, Conrad N, Mutsvangwa T, Rangaka MX, Douglas TS. A user-centred design framework for mHealth. PLoS One. 2020;15(8):e0237910.Mackillop L, Hirst JE, Bartlett KJ, et al. Comparing the efficacy of a mobile phone-based blood glucose management system with standard clinic care in women with gestational diabetes: randomized controlled trial. JMIR mHealth and uHealth. 2018;6(3):e71.Rajkomar A, Dean J, Kohane I. Machine learning in medicine. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(14):1347-1358. doi:10.1056/NEJMra1814259Dunjko V, Briegel H. Machine learning & artificial intelligence in the quantum domain: a review of recent progress. Rep Prog Phys. 2018;8(17):074001.Peleg M, Shahar Y, Quaglini S, et al. MobiGuide: a personalized and patient-centric decision-support system and its evaluation in the atrial fibrillation and gestational diabetes domains. User Model User-Adap Inter. 2017;27(2):159-213.Fung NLS, Widya I, Broens T, et al. Application of a conceptual framework for the modelling and execution of clinical guidelines as networks of concurrent processes. Procedia Comput Sci. 2014;35:671-680.García-Sáez G, Rigla M, Martínez-Sarriegui I, et al. Patient-oriented computerized clinical guidelines for mobile decision support in gestational diabetes. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2014;8(2):238-246.Peleg M, Shahar Y, Quaglini S, et al. Assessment of a personalized and distributed patient guidance system. Int J Med Informatics. 2017;101:108-130.Rigla M, Martínez-Sarriegui I, García-Sáez G, Pons B, Hernando ME. Gestational diabetes management using smart mobile telemedicine. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2018;12(2):260-264.Shalom E, Shahar Y, Goldstein A, et al. Implementation of a distributed guideline-based decision support model within a patient-guidance framework. In: Conference on Artificial Intelligence in Medicine in Europe. Springer; 2015:111-125.Bilici E, Despotou G, Arvanitis TN. The use of computer-interpretable clinical guidelines to manage care complexities of patients with multimorbid conditions: a review. Digital Health. 2018;4:2055207618804927.Jiang F, Jiang Y, Zhi H, et al. Artificial intelligence in healthcare: past, present and future. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2017;2(4):230-243.Moreira MW, Rodrigues JJ, Kumar N, Al-Muhtadi J, Korotaev V. Evolutionary radial basis function network for gestational diabetes data analytics. J Comput Sci. 2018;27:410-417.Caballero-Ruiz E, García-Sáez G, Rigla M, Villaplana M, Pons B, Hernando ME. Automatic classification of glycaemia measurements to enhance data interpretation in an expert system for gestational diabetes. Expert Syst Appl. 2016;63:386-396.Hu Y, Sun Y, Zhang F, Guo B. SmartCarb: an intelligent mobile system to assist diet control for gestational diabetes patients using deep learning neural networks. In: International Conference of Health Informatics and Medical Systems; 2018.Srivastava Y, Khanna P, Kumar S. Estimation of Gestational Diabetes Mellitus using Azure AI Services. In: 2019 Amity International Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AICAI). IEEE; 2019:321-326.Abejirinde I-OO, Douwes R, Bardají A, et al. Pregnant women’s experiences with an integrated diagnostic and decision support device for antenatal care in Ghana. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2018;18(1):209.Pustozerov E, Popova P, Tkachuk A, Bolotko Y, Yuldashev Z, Grineva E. Development and evaluation of a mobile personalized blood glucose prediction system for patients with gestational diabetes mellitus. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2018;6(1):e6.Pustozerov E, Popova P. Mobile-based decision support system for gestational diabetes mellitus. In: 2018 Ural Symposium on Biomedical Engineering, Radioelectronics and Information Technology (USBEREIT). IEEE; 2018:45-48.Volanski W, Prado ALD, Al-Lahham Y, et al. d-GDM: A mobile diagnostic decision support system for gestational diabetes. Arch Endocrinol Metab. 2019;63(5):524-530. doi: 10.20945/2359-3997000000171NHS. Patient data and confidential patient information. Secondary Patient data and confidential patient information. https://digital.nhs.uk/services/national-data-opt-out/understanding-the-national-data-opt-out/confidential-patient-informationNHS. Data Access Request Service (DARS): guidance notes on security. Secondary Data Access Request Service (DARS): guidance notes on security. https://digital.nhs.uk/services/data-access-request-service-dars/data-access-request-service-dars-process/data-access-request-service-dars-guidance-notes-on-securityDouali N, Dollon J, Jaulent MC. Personalized prediction of gestational Diabetes using a clinical decision support system. In: 2015 IEEE International Conference on Fuzzy Systems (FUZZ-IEEE). IEEE; 2015:1-5.Caballero-Ruiz E, García-Sáez G, Rigla M, Villaplana M, Pons B, Hernando ME. A web-based clinical decision support system for gestational diabetes: automatic diet prescription and detection of insulin needs. Int J Med Informatics. 2017;102:35-49.Bromuri S, Puricel S, Schumann R, Krampf J, Ruiz J, Schumacher M. An expert personal health system to monitor patients affected by gestational diabetes mellitus: a feasibility study. J Ambient Intell Smart Environ. 2016;8(2):219-237.Vuppalapati C. Building Enterprise IoT Applications. CRC Press; 2019.Ligo AK, Peha JM. Spectrum for V2X: allocation and sharing. IEEE Trans Cogn Commun Netw. 2019;5(3):768-779. doi:10.1109/TCCN.2019.2916026Albert L, Capel I, García-Sáez G, Martín-Redondo P, Hernando ME, Rigla M. Managing gestational diabetes mellitus using a smartphone application with artificial intelligence (SineDie) during the COVID-19 pandemic: Much more than just telemedicine. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2020;169.Pustozerov E, Tkachuk A, Vasukova E, et al. The role of glycemic index and glycemic load in the development of real-time postprandial glycemic response prediction models for patients with gestational diabetes. Nutrients. 2020;12(2):302.Popova P, Tkachuk A, Vasukova E, Dronova A, Bolotko Y, Pustozerov E, Grineva E. Randomized controlled trial of different intensities of glycemic control in women with gestational diabetes. In: 22nd European Congress of Endocrinology (Vol. 70). BioScientifica; 2020.Fenton N, Neil M. Risk Assessment and Decision Analysis with Bayesian Networks. CRC Press; 2012. doi:10.1201/b21982Artzi NS, Shilo S, Hadar E, et al. Prediction of gestational diabetes based on nationwide electronic health records. Nat Med. 2020;26(1):71-76. doi:10.1038/s41591-019-0724-8Shen J, Chen J, Zheng Z, et al. An innovative artificial intelligence-based app for the diagnosis of gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM-AI): development study. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22(9):e21573. doi:10.2196/21573Kyrimi E, McLachlan S, Dube K, Fenton N. Bayesian Networks in Healthcare: the chasm between research enthusiasm and clinical adoption. medRxiv. 2020.Kyrimi E, Dube K, Fenton NE, et al. Bayesian networks in healthcare: what is preventing their adoption? Artif Intell Med. 2021;116:102079.Kyrimi E, Dube K, Fenton N, et al. Bayesian networks in healthcare: what is preventing their adoption? Artif Intell Med. 2021;116:102079.Reddy S, Fox J, Purohit MP. Artificial intelligence-enabled healthcare delivery. J R Soc Med. 2019;112(1):22-28.